#### Contact

maisomarik@gmail.com

www.linkedin.com/in/mais-omari (LinkedIn)

### Languages

Arabic (Native or Bilingual)
Hebrew (Elementary)
English (Professional Working)

# Mais Omari

MSc Management | Project Management Professional Palestinian Authority

# Summary

A believer in enhancing innovation, critical thinking and analytical skill. A native of the Arabic language and fluent in English with an eagerness to learn and gain practical as well as academic knowledge to support the work experience.

# Experience

Education for Employment Palestine EFE-P Project Officer July 2021 - Present (1 year 7 months) Jerusalem, Palestine

RJ McLeod Contractors Itd.
Assistant Project Manager
June 2019 - September 2019 (4 months)
Glasgow, United Kingdom

With 400 employees, the civil engineering company is taking a step forward towards change to optimise its capabilities, enhance its safety procedures and reduce paper waste.

#### Role:

- Led the implementation of a disruptive innovation project with the goal of transforming traditional paper-based site operations into digitalised operations.
- Identified risks affiliated with changing from paper-based to digitalisation within the construction industry, particularly for RJ McLeod.
- Arranged and managed a one-month digitalisation trial across three different sites to deduce the strengths and weaknesses of the platform of choice.
- Developed a strategy for diffusing digitalisation at project sites.

The Palestinian Circus School
Public Relations and Fundraising Officer
December 2017 - August 2018 (9 months)

Birzeit, Palestine

The Palestinian Circus School is a non-profit, non-governmental organisation that teaches circus to Palestinians across the West Bank. Established in 2006 to develop the creative potential of young people specifically those from less privileged backgrounds, including children with special needs in addition to rehabilitation centres, and providing them with the much-needed empowerment and sense of self-worth. The school currently has a total of 300 students- ages 6-24.

#### Role:

- •Coordinated and brainstormed ideas with designers on layout and image of all promotional materials for Circus theatre screenings whilst meeting deadlines.
- Contacted local and international media outlets such as Rayya FM, Al Jazeera, and Xinhuanet to promote the premiering of circus productions.
- Administered the Circus Facebook page to update followers of Circus activities and productions.
- Formulated detailed interim and annual reports to keep donors connected with day to day activities and progress of circus goals.
- Communicated with potential donors and introduced them to the Circus (history, vision and mission).

Consolidated Contractors International Company 3 years 6 months

Assistant to Country Manager & Document Control April 2017 - November 2017 (8 months)

Palestinian Territory

Also known as CCC House, a state-of-the-art commercial complex is considered an iconic landmark integrating modern architecture and urban textures of Palestine. After 2 years of construction the project was finalised on December 31st, 2015 at a total area of 20,600 m2 and 13 floors high. The US \$26,943,199 building represents the founders dream of having a tangible presence in their childhood home with a total revenue of US \$2,001,756 since 2015 to date.

#### Role:

•Reviewed tender document requirements and specifications, and prepared technical proposals (forms, method statements, work execution plans and Health Safety Environmental Plans) for Noor Utility Scale Solar PV Plants Project (estimated value US \$24,000,000) and EPC 400-450 MWe Jenin

Power Plant Project (estimated value US \$450,000,000) whilst working within a team of specialised engineers.

- Advanced an easy access archive for running projects to reduce time and increase efficiency amongst staff.
- •Developed official company publications and correspondence with guidance from company engineers for 2 running projects (PMA and Museum).

#### Administrative Assistant

August 2016 - April 2017 (9 months)

Palestinian Territory

Project: The Palestine Monetary Authority (PMA)

An independent public institution responsible for the formulation and implementation of monetary and banking policies. Built over an area of 22,646m2, Consolidated Contractors Company completed the US \$28,165,370.53 project on April 2017.

#### Role:

- Prepared Project Manager correspondence pertaining instructions to subcontractors as well as communications with the client to then be verified by the project manager.
- Carried out daily reports, data entry, organised document submittals and shop drawings, prepared correspondence and provided team support to all departments (Planning, Architectural, Electromechanical and Civil) to maintain a smooth work flow and avoid delays.

#### Administrative Assistant

June 2014 - August 2016 (2 years 3 months)

Palestinian Territory

Project: The Palestinian Museum

Located on a 40,000m2 plot next to Birzeit University campus, on a hill overlooking the Mediterranean, the Museum is the first steel structure building of its kind in Palestine with a total value of US \$25,000,000.

#### Role:

- •Accelerated reporting process for more efficient work results between departments.
- Composed correspondence detailing activities in need of improvement and/ or re-design and/or re-work to be dispatched to designers, engineers, and subcontractors.

- Guided field visits with an introduction on the project for students, donors, and clients whilst maintaining all safety protocols.
- Entrusted with petty cash and invoices. A monthly report is sent to the financial department with petty cash request when needed.

#### **AMIDEAST**

Testing Programme Coordinator October 2012 - September 2013 (1 year)

Palestinian Territory

A non for profit organisation with a long-term commitment to strengthening Palestinian human resources and institutions through expanded education and training services, technical assistance, and scholarship and grant programs.

#### Roles:

Managing the Testing Department:

- Providing customer service via telephone/ e-mail/ face to face which included problem solving and damage control, guiding and providing test registrations, authenticating U.S. University/College degrees, and providing translation services (AE-EA).
- Forming and training a team of proctors to achieve the best services for the client and customer.
- Delegating and overseeing tasks to the Testing Assistant and Test Administrators.
- Staying up to date with the latest examinations around the world.
- Updating testing related information on the AMIDEAST website and Facebook page.

Managing the PROMETRIC Testing Center:

- Making sure that the Proctors follow PROMETRIC regulations.
- Overseeing all Proctors are certified by PROMETRIC and all regulations are implemented.
- Resolving any technical problems without interfering with test subjects.
- Reporting to Country Director and PROMETRIC.

## Education

Cranfield School of Management

Master of Science - MS, Management · (2018 - 2019)

Birzeit University

Bachelor of Arts - BA, English Language and Literature, General · (2007 - 2011)

Birzeit University

Bachelor of Arts - BA, English Language and Literature,

General · (2007 - 2011)